<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-08-02T14:01:11+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jacques Saraydaryan</title><subtitle>A Short description about my activities and interests ...
</subtitle><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">IROS 2024 - Multi-Robot Navigation Among Movable Obstacles - Implicit Coordination to Deal with Conflicts and Deadlocks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/07/01/MR-NAMO/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IROS 2024 - Multi-Robot Navigation Among Movable Obstacles - Implicit Coordination to Deal with Conflicts and Deadlocks" /><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/07/01/MR-NAMO</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/07/01/MR-NAMO/"><![CDATA[<p>As a first approach to this new problem, we introduce and compare variants of an implicit coordination strategy allowing the use of existing NAMO algorithms in a Multi-Robot context. We also show how our previously introduced social occupation cost model can improve the efficiency of multi-robot plans with better obstacle placement choices, and how it can be applied in a novel way to find relevant robot placement choices in deadlock situations.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to find efficient paths for multiple robots in modifiable cluttered environments? This question leads us to formulate the new problem of Multi-Robot Navigation Among Movable Obstacles (MR-NAMO). In MR-NAMO, robots must not only plan for the possibility of displacing obstacles as needed to facilitate their navigation, but also solve conflicts that may arise when trying to simultaneously access a location or obstacle...]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">AAMAS 2024 - Attention Graph for Multi-Robot Social Navigation with Deep Reinforcement Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/06/30/MultiSoc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AAMAS 2024 - Attention Graph for Multi-Robot Social Navigation with Deep Reinforcement Learning" /><published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/06/30/MultiSoc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2024/06/30/MultiSoc/"><![CDATA[<p>First an edge-selector produces a sparse graph, then a crowd coordinator applies node attention to produce a graph representing the influence of each entity on the others. This is incorporated into a model-free RL framework to learn multi-agent policies. We evaluate our approach on simulation and provide a series of experiments in a set of various conditions (number of agents / pedestrians). Empirical results show that our method learns faster than social navigation deep RL mono-agent techniques, and enables efficient multi-agent implicit coordination in challenging crowd navigation with multiple heterogeneous humans. Furthermore, by incorporating customizable meta-parameters, we can adjust the neighborhood density to take into account in our navigation strategy.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning robot navigation strategies among pedes- trian is crucial for domain based applications. Combining perception, planning and prediction allows us to model the interactions between robots and pedestrians, resulting in im- pressive outcomes especially with recent approaches based on deep reinforcement learning (RL). However, these works do not consider multi-robot scenarios. In this paper, we present MultiSoc, a new method for learning multi-agent socially aware navigation strategies using RL. Inspired by recent works on multi-agent deep RL, our method leverages graph-based representation of agent interactions, combining the positions and fields of view of entities (pedestrians and agents). Each agent uses a model based on two Graph Neural Network combined with attention mechanisms...]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">RCS 2023 - Human Presence Probability Map (HPP) a Probability propagation based on Human Flow Grid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2023/07/18/HppMap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RCS 2023 - Human Presence Probability Map (HPP) a Probability propagation based on Human Flow Grid" /><published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2023/07/18/HppMap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2023/07/18/HppMap/"><![CDATA[<p>This process provides real-time information about the most probable region on the map where humans can be found. We propose a new problem representation allowing us to efficiently parallelize the propagation. To deal with the learned model and the real time robot observations, we propose to include a gaussian rotation probability process (VonMises) combined with the previous learned observation to adapt the propagation. A set of experiments has been conduced with simulated environments that include real data allowing us to evaluate the model and to compare with the standard approaches.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personal assistance, delivery services, and crowd navigation through robots fleet are complex activities that involve human-robot interaction and fleet coordination. Human location estimation is one of the key factors in assisting robots in their tasks. This paper proposes an efficient process for propagating human presence Probability based on partial observation of humans by the robot fleet...]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="fr"><title type="html">Navigation Among Crowd - DEEP-RL - (Master 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2022/09/01/DSRNN-NavAmong-Crowd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigation Among Crowd - DEEP-RL - (Master 2)" /><published>2022-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2022/09/01/DSRNN-NavAmong-Crowd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2022/09/01/DSRNN-NavAmong-Crowd/"><![CDATA[<p>The following works compare different crowd navigation strategies. The work focuses on Deep-RL technics. 
To do so the <a href="https://github.com/Shuijing725/CrowdNav_DSRNN">crowNav</a> simulator has been used and some <a href="https://github.com/michelland/DSRNN">improvements</a> made to add more realistic hypotheses.
The <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.04820">DS-RNN</a> deep-RL has been used as baseline and improve to fit new conditions.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/actu/post/Post-DS-RNN_AE.gif" alt="DS-RNN Update Behavior" title="DS-RNN Update Behavior" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following project refers to the results of a Master 2 work, investing different Deep-RL methods to help robot to navigate among Crowd.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Navigation Local Planner tutorial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/10/05/Tuto-LocalPlanner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigation Local Planner tutorial" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/10/05/Tuto-LocalPlanner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/10/05/Tuto-LocalPlanner/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following project refers to a tutorial on local planner, DWA is studied and different configurations are tested on environment containing known and unknown obstacles.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Robocup, OPL and SSPL competition results</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/07/16/Robocup-2021-overall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robocup, OPL and SSPL competition results" /><published>2021-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/07/16/Robocup-2021-overall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/07/16/Robocup-2021-overall/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following video shows the result of the LyonTech Robocup team in the RoboCup@Home international competition in both OPL (Open Plateform League) and SSPL (Social Standard Plateform League)]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Robocup, Manage spatial information</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/03/10/ROS-Robocup-worldmng/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robocup, Manage spatial information" /><published>2021-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/03/10/ROS-Robocup-worldmng</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2021/03/10/ROS-Robocup-worldmng/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following repository provides a set of tools to manage spatial information into a Postgis DB. Collected bounding boxes are converted into 3d points (PCL) and clustered using a DBSCAN (x,y,z,category). Clusters are them registered into Postgis DB. More information here https://github.com/jacques-saraydaryan/ros_world_mng/tree/dev_palbator_postgis_js]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">IROS 2020, S-NAMO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/11/18/IRos-S-NAMO/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IROS 2020, S-NAMO" /><published>2020-11-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/11/18/IRos-S-NAMO</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/11/18/IRos-S-NAMO/"><![CDATA[<p>The paper is available here <a href="https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-02912925/document">HAL</a>. Paper reference:  B. Renault, J. Saraydaryan, O. Simonin, “Modeling a Social Placement Cost to Extend Navigation Among Movable Obstacles (NAMO) Algorithms”. In 2020 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2020.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication of Benoit Renault in the IROS International conference, NAMO (NavigationAmong Movable Obstacles) is a domain where robots move objets in order to reach their objectives.This paper, Modeling a Social Placement Cost to Extend NavigationAmong Movable Obstacles (NAMO) Algorithms, intends to optimize object placement choices regarding some social constraints (not in the middle, narrow is worth, not breaking room connectivity).]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Robotic Tutorial, Particle filter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/09/13/Ros-tuto-navigation-ros-nav-stack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robotic Tutorial, Particle filter" /><published>2020-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/09/13/Ros-tuto-navigation-ros-nav-stack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2020/09/13/Ros-tuto-navigation-ros-nav-stack/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following repository provides a tutorial work on using a particle filter for robot localization. Here a simple plane simulation is used to manipulate particle filter. more information here https://github.com/jacques-saraydaryan/particles_filter_plane_simulator_student]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">RoboCup@Home 2020 - TDP OpenPlateform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/actu/2019/11/13/Robocup-2020-TDPOpenPlateForme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RoboCup@Home 2020 - TDP OpenPlateform" /><published>2019-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/actu/2019/11/13/Robocup-2020-TDPOpenPlateForme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/actu/2019/11/13/Robocup-2020-TDPOpenPlateForme/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Jacques Saraydaryan</name><email>&lt;mail@domain.tld&gt;</email></author><category term="actu" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lyontech team will participate to the RoboCup@Home 2020 in the league OpenPlateforme, the following video shows the team and robot capacity needed for the qualification process. More information is available [here](https://robocup-lyontech.github.io/opl/)]]></summary></entry></feed>